<labelListing><text><rawText>b'Copyright Notice  \xc2\xa92000-2005 David A. Solomon and Mark Russinovich  * These materials are part of the CRK (aka Windows Operating System Internals Curriculum Resource Kit), developed by David A. Solomon and Mark E. Russinovich with Andreas Polze  * Microsoft has licensed these materials from David Solomon Expert Seminars, Inc. for distribution to academic organizations solely for use in academic environments (and not for commercial use)'</rawText><rawText>b'Basic Information  # Windows Operating Systems Internals is a pool of material and resources that explains operating systems (O8) concepts based on the Microsoft Windows NT operating system family,  structured following the ACM/IEEE Operating System Body of Knowledge (\'BOK\xc2\xae) as defined in Computing Curriculum 2001 project by the Joint IEEE and ACM Task Force (\'CC2001)  * This curriculum is based on the book "Windows Internals\xc2\xae, by Mark Russinovich and David Solomon.'</rawText><rawText>b'Roadmap for Section 1.1.  * ACM/IEEE Operating Systems Body of Knowledge - Core units  * ACM/IEEE Operating Systems Body of Knowledge - Elective units  * Supplementary units'</rawText><rawText>b'Unit 12: Scripting  * 12. Scripting (Elective)  * 12.1. Windows Management Instrumentation * 12.2. The Registry  w'</rawText><rawText>b'Supplementary Unit A: Windows Networking  * A.1. Networking Components in Windows OS (Supplementary/Advanced)  * A.2. Windows Socket Programming (Supplementary/Advanced)  * A.3. Microsoft-specific extensions to Sockets and other Networking APIs (Supplementary/Advanced)  i'</rawText><rawText>b'Supplementary Units B:  Comparing the Linux and Windows Kernels  * B. Comparing the Linux and Windows Kernels (Supplementary/Advanced)  * B.1. Linux and Windows Comparison (Supplementary/Advanced)     w'</rawText><rawText>b'Supplementary Units C: Windows - Unix Interoperability  * C. Windows - Unix Interoperability (Supplementary/Advanced)  * C.1. File and Command Interoperability (Supplementary/Advanced)  * C.2. Programming (Supplementary/Advanced)  w'</rawText><rawText>b'Suggested Reading  \xc2\xae Pavel Yosifovich, Alex lonescu, et al., "Windows Internals", 7th Edition, Microsoft Press, 2017.  * (This book is the course\'s direct companion - required reading).  \xc2\xae Abraham Silberschatz, Peter B. Galvin, Operating System Concepts, John Wiley &amp; Sons, 6th Ed., 2003;  * (This book gives a platform-neutral overview on operating system design and implementation - suggested reaing)  \xc2\xae Jeffrey Richter, Programming Applications for Microsoft Windows, 4th Edition, Microsoft Press, September 1999.  * (This book provides a comprehensive discussion of the Windows API - suggested reading).  w'</rawText><rawText>b"Suggested Reading (contd.)  * Johnson M. Hart, Win32 System Programming: A Windows\xc2\xae 2000 Application Developer's Guide, 2nd Edition, Addison-Wesley, 2000.  * (This book discusses select Windows programming problems and addresses the problem of portable programming by comparing Windows and Unix approaches)  * Andrew S. Tanenbaum, Distributed Operating Systems, Prentice Hall, 1995.  * (This text accompanies the course's advanced modules and offers students an explanation of the concepts of distributed operating systems).  * hitps/www.sysinternals.com * (Tools useful for experiments wih Windows internals) * hitp:/imsdn.mierosoft.com * (Oni resource for information on APIs required during work on labs}  a"</rawText></text><titlu /><autor /><editura><rawText>b'Unit 1: Overview of Operating Systems  1.1. Windows Operating System Internals Course Overview'</rawText></editura><isbn /></labelListing>